Vignesh Arunachalam

https://vigneshrapport.github.io in https://www.linkedin.com/in/vignesh-arunachalam-60073b11b

PROFILE

Lead .NET developer with 8+ years of experience in analysing, designing, developing, and maintaining web applications using Microsoft and open-source technologies. M.Phil. graduate.

Involved software development life cycle with responsibilities of analysing, designing, developing, and implementing various new features, analysing the bugs to identify the root cause, and giving the solution, the enhancement or improving existing system by giving best solutions.

SKILLS

.NET, C#, ASP.NET MVC, .NET Core, ASP.NET Core MVC, ReactJS, SQL Server, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Azure DevOps, DevExpress Dashboard/ Report. Domains - Civil Construction , SIEM (SSOC), Textile (Garments), ETL.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Developer - Balfour Beatty Infrastructure India Private Limited

Working as lead developer with responsibilities of writing testable, scalable, and efficient code. Reviewing developers code, pull requests and suggesting them if anything can be improved. Deploying application into various environments. Mentoring and helping team members to resolve issues and solve technical problems.

Application Developer - Balfour Beatty Infrastructure India Private Limited

Working with UK teams with responsibilities of get requirements, developing and delivering new features and enhancements. Implemented a new feature or upgrade an existing feature to meet the needs of the end user. Works independently when required.

Associate Software Developer - SISA Information Security Private Limited

Involved software product development with responsibilities of analysing, designing, and developing web application. Implementing various new features & enhancements. Analysing the bugs to identify the root cause & fixing them, improving existing system by giving best solutions. Integrating third-party tool (DevExpress Dashboard) into application.

Junior Software Engineer - Valuesoft Solutions Private Limited

Involved in analysing, designing, and developing web & desktop applications. Understanding the current system, collecting the existing application difficulties and new expectations.

Intern under work integrated learning model - Valuesoft Solutions Private Limited

Worked as Intern under work integrated learning model. Involved in the core behind coding of web & windows projects.

06/2017 - 05/2018

04/2022 - present

06/2020 - 03/2022

06/2018 - 05/2020

Bangalore, India

Bangalore, India

Bangalore, India

Bangalore, India

06/2015 - 05/2017

Bangalore, India

EDUCATION

M.Phil. (Computer Science) - Sri Ramakrishna Mission Vidyalaya College of Arts and Science (Affiliated to Bharathiyar University)

Graduated in Second Class. Presented **International Conference Paper** on Recent Trends in Advanced Computing.

2017 – 2021 Coimbatore

M.C.A. (Computer Applications) - Sri Ramakrishna Mission Vidyalaya College of Arts and Science (Affiliated to Bharathiyar University)

2015 – 2017 Coimbatore

Graduated in First Class with Distinction (D+) & 81.94%. 1st Rank holder of department of M.C.A.

B.Sc. (Computer Science) - Sri Ramakrishna Mission Vidyalaya College of Arts and Science (Affiliated to Bharathiyar University)

2012 – 2015 Coimbatore

Graduated in First Class with Distinction (D+) & 81.59%. Best Out Going Student of the Year, 1st Rank holder of department of B.Sc. Computer Science.

PROJECTS

• Project : AIMS (Civil Construction Domain) • Role : Lead Developer • Project Type : Web Application • Technologies Applied : .NET Core , C#, ASP.NET MVC Core, Microsoft SQL Server, Material-UI.

2021 - present

AIMS is digital solutions to deliver lean job / activity management. This will encourage continuous improvement, measure progress and track performance, improve communication, encourage teamwork and collaboration, provide a forum for staff to raise issues. The application provides a central point to display up-to-date, team-specific information.

• Project : Project Portal (Civil Construction Domain) • Role : Software Developer • Project Type : Web Application • Technologies Applied : .NET Core , C#, ASP.NET MVC Core, SQL Server, Bootstrap.

2020 - 2021

A single place for a project manager to view, drilldown and rollup all project related data, in real-time, from multiple sources, minimizing effort by avoiding duplication when collating the data, whilst also providing a view of the overall company structure promoting a commonality in terminology.

• Project : GIN (Civil Infrastructure Domain) • Role : Software Developer • Project Type : Web Application • Technologies Applied : React-JS, Python, The Django Rest Framework

2020 - 2021

GNI - Digital collaborative tool

• Project : SISA EOT (SIEM S-SOC Domain) • Role : Software Developer • Project Type : Web Application • Technologies Applied : .NET, C#, ASP .NET MVC, SQL, DevExpress Dashboard/Reports.

2018 - 2020

SISA EOT (SIEM S-SOC) tool is a log analysis and monitoring product of SISA. It processes millions of logs and sends real time alerts based on critical events and correlation rules.

• Project : ACL Imports and Exports (Garments - Textiles Domain) • Role : Software Developer • Project Type : Web Application • Technologies Applied : .NET , C#, ASP.MVC 5, Entity Framework, and SQL Server

2015 - 2018

ACL is into textile business, which is operating in 4 countries. ACL has own custom developed ERP system which was developed using VB 6 with MS SQL. The same application is customized according to the country-based operations. The new system is designed and developed as a web based centralized system of which can be accessed by all the 4 country users seamlessly.

DECLARATION

Hereby, I declare that the above information furnished by me is true to the best of my knowledge and belief. I assure that if I am given an opportunity, I will execute my work to the satisfaction of my superiors.